<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="//petermolnar.net/feed/atom.xsl"?>
<atom:feed xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/</atom:id>
  <atom:title>Latest entries from petermolnar.net</atom:title>
  <atom:updated>2021-06-27T21:10:00+01:00</atom:updated>
  <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
  <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
  <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  <atom:icon>https://petermolnar.net/favicon.png</atom:icon>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/journal/amikor-az-internet-felfalja-magat/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>"Lehúztuk az LD50.hu-t a hálózatról"</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-07-10T07:11:23+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-06-27T21:10:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Molnár Péter</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/journal/amikor-az-internet-felfalja-magat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>journal</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">"a hálózati külső memóriában ezek egyszerű emlékek, amelyek előhívása, cseréje és átdolgozása számunkra annyira nyilvánvaló, mint nektek a Négy páncélos és a kutya felidézése."</atom:summary>
    <atom:content type="html">"a hálózati külső memóriában ezek egyszerű emlékek, amelyek előhívása, cseréje és átdolgozása számunkra annyira nyilvánvaló, mint nektek a Négy páncélos és a kutya felidézése."

&lt;p&gt;A fenti szöveg egy idézet Piotr Czerski &amp;quot;Mi, a háló gyermekei&amp;quot; című, inkább manifesztó, mint essé írásából. Stílusosan kénytelen voltam az archive.org-on megkeresni&lt;a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; mert sajnos balga módon csak a linket mentettem el 2012-ben a magyar fordításhoz, és azóta az oldal úgy tűnik, rég halott - de még a google sem volt hajnaldó találatot adni a &amp;quot;Mi, a háló gyerekei&amp;quot; kifejezésre. Fájdalmasan releváns mind a témámhoz, mind az esszéhez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A minap a Spotify listáimat takarítva meg akartam látogatni egy weboldalt, hogy megnézzek a setlistet egy buliból, amin idestova több, mint egy évtizede tomboltunk. Az említett oldal egy teljesen egyedi, évtizedekkel a korát megelőző furcsaság volt, ami egy blogból kinőve maga köré tekerte Magyarország szokatlan, sötét, deviáns, a &amp;quot;normálistól&amp;quot; eltérő szukbultúráját amennyiben annak bármilyen köze volt a cyberpunk - goth - industrial vonalhoz, akár csak érintőlegesen is. Az egyetlen közösség, amiben valaha otthon éreztem magam, hasonló különc emberek között.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Az oldalt a tulajdonosai 2012-ben lezárták, és áttették &amp;quot;csak olvasható&amp;quot; módba - akkor és ott ez olyan sokként ért, hogy az eleve szar 2012-t életem egyik legkaotikusabb évévé tette, aminek a végén Angliában kötöttünk ki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure property="image" vocab="http://schema.org/" typeof="ImageObject"&gt;
&lt;span data-property="name" content="ld50-eol"&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;picture&gt; &lt;img src="https://petermolnar.net/journal/amikor-az-internet-felfalja-magat/ld50-eol.jpg" property="contentUrl" title="ld50-eol.jpg" alt="A bejelentés, ami olyan dühöt váltott ki belőlem, hogy vállalhatatlan
bejegyzéseket hagytam alatta - természetesen elnézést kértem pár
oldallal később" width="553" height="691" loading="lazy" /&gt; &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;span class="alt" data-property="caption"&gt;A bejelentés, ami olyan dühöt váltott ki belőlem, hogy vállalhatatlan bejegyzéseket hagytam alatta - természetesen elnézést kértem pár oldallal később&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Egy darabig próbálkoztunk &amp;quot;utód&amp;quot; oldalt készíteni, de elvérzett. Akkor úgy gondoltam, hogy azért, mert nem volt téma, vagy érdeklődés, de aztán 2018 környékén belebotlottam egy dokumentumfilm-sorozatba a BBS korszakról&lt;a href="#fn2" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref2"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; . Ez a technológia Magyarországot szerintem teljesen elkerülte, lévén a 80as években otthoni telefonok közötti direkt számítógépkapcsolat kellett volna hozzá, itt meg sok helyen a 90es évek elejéig nem volt vonalas telefon sem otthon, nemhogy számítógép és modem. Valahol a többórányi anyagban elhangzott egy, az témához vágó mondat: a távolsági hívások ára miatt ezek a közösségek annyira lokálisak voltak, hogy ha valaki bedobta, hogy pizza holnap XY helyen, akkor sokan meg is jelentek a közösségből.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ez volt az, ami felett én annak idején átsiklottam: a mixed reality &lt;em&gt;(fogalmam sincs, van-e jobb kifejezés erre az esetre; ha igen kérlek írd meg nekem)&lt;/em&gt; vonatkozás. Az, hogy ez nem csak egy tematikus online fórum, sőt, utólag visszatekintve sok esetben az online rész másodlagos volt, hanem egyfajta kiterjesztése a valóságnak, hogy tovább folyhassanak az életben megkezdett beszélgetések. Máskor, másnak, egy egyszerű mód, hogy felmérje a terepet, mielőtt személyesen odamerészkedik valahova.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2021 van, és a munkahelyem kettészakadt annak tekintetében, hogy visszamenjünk-e az irodába, vagy maradjon minden távmunkában &lt;em&gt;(értelemszerűen eszem ágában sincs visszamenni az irodába)&lt;/em&gt;. A legérdekesebb az, hogy erről a vitáról az Amerikai Pite ugrott be: az, hogy egy megosztott live webcam feedet 1999-ben az iskola java része megnézett, mert teljesen normális volt az, hogy miután hazamentünk a kötelező órákról, folytattuk a beszélgetést a neten, legyen az IRC, ICQ, MSN, bármi más. A különbség 2021-hez képest az, hogy mindezt az ember egy fix helyen lakó számítógép elé ülve tette - pont, mint az otthonról végzett munka. &lt;em&gt;A hely/zetváltoztatás lehetősége csak kivételesen keveknek adatott meg, mer a laptop ritka és drága dolog volt, a telefonok meg 10 sms-t jó, ha tárolni tudtak.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amit mondani akarok, hogy amiben mi felnőttünk, más volt, mint ami ma van. Az internet nem volt a zsebünkben, nem jött velünk bulizni, nem dokumentálta az összes csetlésünket és botlásunkat, viszont talán pont emiatt lehetett egy online közösségi térben folytani, amit a valóságban megkedztünk. Úgy gondolom, hogy az oldal legértékesebb része az a lehetőség volt, hogy a programajánlók nem tűntek el az esemény után: sokszor követték beszámolók, fotókkal, feltörekvő hobbifotósoktól, és hozzászólásokkal, mintegy dokumentálva a rendezvény utóéletét.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ma, amikor a lopják-az-adatod-manipulálnak-mindmeghalunk balhék egymást érik, úgy tűnik, hogy az ilyenfajta, mixed reality (?) közösségek szinte teljesen felszívódtak. Nincs hol folytatni a beszélgetést egy élményről, mert azonnak eltűnik a falakról - kell a hely a trendingnek és a reklámnak. Minden instant, minden vagy most történik, vagy felejtsd el annak a reményét is, hogy előkerüljön még egyszer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vissza a mai naphoz és a setlisthez: az oldalt két héttel ezelőtt törölték. Ami fogadott, egy pár soros landing page, a régi design-nal. Bejelentés? Egy böffenet Facebookon, törlés után.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure property="image" vocab="http://schema.org/" typeof="ImageObject"&gt;
&lt;span data-property="name" content="deleted"&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;picture&gt; &lt;img src="https://petermolnar.net/journal/amikor-az-internet-felfalja-magat/deleted.png" property="contentUrl" title="deleted.png" alt="Ennyi? Ilyen érzése lehetett a Geocities törlése, vagy a MySpace
adatvesztése." width="602" height="148" loading="lazy" /&gt; &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;span class="alt" data-property="caption"&gt;Ennyi? Ilyen érzése lehetett a Geocities törlése, vagy a MySpace adatvesztése.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Varázsütésre eltűnt sok évnyi közösségi tartalom, flyer, galéria, beszámoló, koncertfotó, pre-myspace gótprofil, és persze kvadrillió fórum flamewar. Egy gombnyomásra törlődött az a &amp;quot;read only múzeum&amp;quot; amit az oldal készítői 2012-ben hagytak, és amire Piotr Czerski &amp;quot;hálózati külső memória&amp;quot;-ként hivatkozott.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eljutottunk volna oda, hogy a modern magánszféra-védelmi törvények miatt törölni kell a múltat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sok jel mutat erre, hiszen több példát láttunk, hogy meghurcolnak valakit évekkel azelőtti, akár még gyerekkorában &lt;em&gt;(emlékeztető: jogilag 18 alatt az ember gyereknek számít)&lt;/em&gt; tett kijelentések, tweetek miatt, olyannyira, hogy az ember inkább maga megy és törli, mielőtt valami elmeháborodott ráakad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persze lehet azt mondani, hogy miért kiábálta ki a világba, gondolta volna végig, de nagyon kevesen vannak, akik 14-18 évesen felfogták, hogy amit akkor gondolnak a világról, az még erősen formálódik és fejlődik.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viszont mi a helyzet egy olyan oldallal, ahol mindenki szabadon választott felhasználónévvel volt jelen - nem a valódi névvel, talán még csak nem is valódi profiképekkel? Ezeket is törölni kell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha töröljük azt, amik, akik voltunk, elveszik a lehetősége, hogy reflektáljunk. Magunkat fosztjuk meg attól, hogy felmérjük: vagyunk-e legalább annyira jó emberek, ahogyan a 10, 20, 30 évvel ezelőtti önmagunk ezt elképzelte?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visszaolvastam évtizedekkel ezelőtti gondolataimat. Vállalnám-e mindent? Igen. Lenne, amiért elnézést kérnék? Természetesen - de majdnem biztos, hogy már meg is tettem. Akárcsak régi barátok, ezek mind fontosak, hogy emlékeztessük magunkat arra, kik vagyunk, mi az utunk, hova jutottunk, és hogy felülvizsgáljuk: a jó ösvényt járjunk?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azonban az online törlések, DMCA-k, Right to Forget, és hasonlók elgondolkoztattak valamin: miért nem vonatkozik ez pl. folyóirat archívumokra? Valakiről lehoznak egy cikket, amiről később kiderül, hogy rágalom - mégsem kérjük a könyvtárakat, hogy semmisítsék meg az archív példányokat, elég egy helyreigazítást leközölni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talán ez a megoldás: talán azokat az oldalakat, amiket törölni akar valaki vagy ki kellene nyomtatnunk, vagy air-gapped könyvtári rendszerekre kellene archiválni. Így a múltunk, a nosztalgiára való lehetőségünk is megmarad, és a magánjogok sem csorbulnak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kár, hogy sok oldalért már késő&lt;a href="#fn3" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref3"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - és ezek között mostantól az ld50.hu is ott szerepel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="footnotes"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn1"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120712164204/http://www.kalozmedia.org/2012/06/19/piotr-czerski-mi-a-halo-gyerekei/" class="uri"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20120712164204/http://www.kalozmedia.org/2012/06/19/piotr-czerski-mi-a-halo-gyerekei/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn2"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgE-9Sxs2IBVgJkY-1ZMj0tIFxsJ-vOkv" class="uri"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgE-9Sxs2IBVgJkY-1ZMj0tIFxsJ-vOkv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="#fnref2" class="footnote-back"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki.archiveteam.org/index.php/Deathwatch" class="uri"&gt;https://wiki.archiveteam.org/index.php/Deathwatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="#fnref3" class="footnote-back"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/pwll-y-wrach-waterfall/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Pwll-y-wrach Waterfalls</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-07-10T07:11:26+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-05-07T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/pwll-y-wrach-waterfall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was finally a real waterfall; the previous one I visited this day turned out to be a tiny stream in the middle of nowhere. Pwll-y-wrach is a small nature reserve, quite easy to climb and have a nice walk, even with family.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/pwll-y-wrach-waterfall/pwll-y-wrach-waterfall_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="169646"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was finally a real waterfall; the previous one I visited this day turned out to be a tiny stream in the middle of nowhere. Pwll-y-wrach is a small nature reserve, quite easy to climb and have a nice walk, even with family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was finally a real waterfall; the previous one I visited this day turned out to be a tiny stream in the middle of nowhere. Pwll-y-wrach is a small nature reserve, quite easy to climb and have a nice walk, even with family.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/talgarth-asylum/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Talgarth Asylum</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-07-10T07:11:28+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-05-06T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/talgarth-asylum/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On my way down from Pwll-y-Wrach, in the distance, I spotted something that on the map was only marked as &amp;quot;hospital&amp;quot;. Apparently I stumbled upon Talgarth Asylum, a clinic that was closed only 20 years ago. In that 20 years, it got stripped of the slate on…&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/talgarth-asylum/talgarth-asylum_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="69122"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On my way down from Pwll-y-Wrach, in the distance, I spotted something that on the map was only marked as &amp;quot;hospital&amp;quot;. Apparently I stumbled upon Talgarth Asylum, a clinic that was closed only 20 years ago. In that 20 years, it got stripped of the slate on…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my way down from Pwll-y-Wrach, in the distance, I spotted something that on the map was only marked as &amp;quot;hospital&amp;quot;. Apparently I stumbled upon Talgarth Asylum, a clinic that was closed only 20 years ago. In that 20 years, it got stripped of the slate on the roof and left to rot. The locals use the field next to it for picnic, among a serious amount of asbestos warning signs - by looking in the windows there's cracked AIB ceiling everywhere, so I got as far as I could fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet then showed me how this place looked only 11 years ago&lt;a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and it's hard to believe how much destruction 11 years of weather - and looting - can do to a place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="footnotes"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn1"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.derelictplaces.co.uk/threads/talgarth-asylum-wales.31652/#post-320711" class="uri"&gt;https://www.derelictplaces.co.uk/threads/talgarth-asylum-wales.31652/#post-320711&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/creek-waterfall/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Waterfall in a creek</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-05-11T11:49:12+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-05-05T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/creek-waterfall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I previously mentioned I went looking for waterfalls in Herefordshire, following markings on openstreetmaps. This was above the marked part of the waterfall, where it was mostly a stream, but I liked this part better, than the real waterfall - which, just…&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/creek-waterfall/creek-waterfall_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="197685"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I previously mentioned I went looking for waterfalls in Herefordshire, following markings on openstreetmaps. This was above the marked part of the waterfall, where it was mostly a stream, but I liked this part better, than the real waterfall - which, just…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I previously mentioned I went looking for waterfalls in Herefordshire, following markings on openstreetmaps. This was above the marked part of the waterfall, where it was mostly a stream, but I liked this part better, than the real waterfall - which, just to note, is basically dried out this time of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to test our new lens, a Pentax 12-24mm (APS-C), and I'm quite positively impressed by the angle (18mm equivalent for full-frame) it's capable of capturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: it was hard to capture this without HDR, but I think it's all right.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/red-hill-herefordshire/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Red Hill in Herefordshire</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-07-10T07:11:26+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-05-04T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/red-hill-herefordshire/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While Nora went on a Japanese woodblock printing course in Herefordshire I had two days to find something interesting around. I ended up pulling up OsmAnd, looking for waterfalls; one of them was marked close to a village called Painscastle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in the …&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/red-hill-herefordshire/red-hill-herefordshire_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="51850"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While Nora went on a Japanese woodblock printing course in Herefordshire I had two days to find something interesting around. I ended up pulling up OsmAnd, looking for waterfalls; one of them was marked close to a village called Painscastle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in the …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Nora went on a Japanese woodblock printing course in Herefordshire I had two days to find something interesting around. I ended up pulling up OsmAnd, looking for waterfalls; one of them was marked close to a village called Painscastle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in the end I found the waterfall - a tiny, but very nice stream in a creek in the middle of nowhere: bog &amp;amp; heather for miles and miles. The photo above was towards one of the directions, the direction where there was something.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/sunset-branches/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Sunset branches</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-07-10T07:11:27+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-05-03T08:45:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/sunset-branches/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We took a small walk from our accommodation in Herefordshire, and the last bits of sunlight somehow came through nicely. I was also testing a new focusing screen in my camera to see if it helps with manual focusing; indeed it does, though my hands need to…&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/sunset-branches/sunset-branches_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="154150"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We took a small walk from our accommodation in Herefordshire, and the last bits of sunlight somehow came through nicely. I was also testing a new focusing screen in my camera to see if it helps with manual focusing; indeed it does, though my hands need to…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a small walk from our accommodation in Herefordshire, and the last bits of sunlight somehow came through nicely. I was also testing a new focusing screen in my camera to see if it helps with manual focusing; indeed it does, though my hands need to be steadier.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/village-of-ford/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Village of Ford</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-07-10T07:11:28+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-05-02T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/village-of-ford/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On our way to Herefordshire we wanted to stop somewhere to eat - because finally it's allowed to sit outside a pub instead of takeaway. When we spotted the Plough in Ford, we stopped, though originally because the view was absurdly beautiful. By the time …&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/village-of-ford/village-of-ford_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="103321"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On our way to Herefordshire we wanted to stop somewhere to eat - because finally it's allowed to sit outside a pub instead of takeaway. When we spotted the Plough in Ford, we stopped, though originally because the view was absurdly beautiful. By the time …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way to Herefordshire we wanted to stop somewhere to eat - because finally it's allowed to sit outside a pub instead of takeaway. When we spotted the Plough in Ford, we stopped, though originally because the view was absurdly beautiful. By the time we got to eating and taking our camera out, the sun was gone, sadly, but even without sunshine on the hills the scene is remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/landscape-in-wales/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Landscape in Wales</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-07-10T07:11:24+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-05-01T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/landscape-in-wales/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This photo is from last year, when the UK rules were relaxed enough to allow some domestic travel, and we went to Snowdonia. We've been there quite a few times, and while we enjoyed it after months of lockdown, the weather was far, from gentle. This doesn…&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/landscape-in-wales/landscape-in-wales_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="69718"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This photo is from last year, when the UK rules were relaxed enough to allow some domestic travel, and we went to Snowdonia. We've been there quite a few times, and while we enjoyed it after months of lockdown, the weather was far, from gentle. This doesn…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This photo is from last year, when the UK rules were relaxed enough to allow some domestic travel, and we went to Snowdonia. We've been there quite a few times, and while we enjoyed it after months of lockdown, the weather was far, from gentle. This doesn't change the fact that the landscape is still fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/foggy-mathematical-bridge/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Foggy Mathematical Bridge</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-05-11T11:49:12+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-04-30T07:35:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/foggy-mathematical-bridge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the continuation of the previous walk; Cambridge in fog is quite a wonderful sight.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/foggy-mathematical-bridge/foggy-mathematical-bridge_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="70980"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the continuation of the previous walk; Cambridge in fog is quite a wonderful sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the continuation of the previous walk; Cambridge in fog is quite a wonderful sight.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/winter-lockdown-in-fog/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Winter lockdown morning in Cambridge</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-05-11T11:49:14+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-04-29T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/winter-lockdown-in-fog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Misty Albion gets misty a lot, but it rarely gets properly foggy. Fog transforms the world into another dimention: one where sounds are soft, views are mysterious, and where mood swings from one end of the spectrum to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tip my hat to anyone who…&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/winter-lockdown-in-fog/winter-lockdown-in-fog_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="74940"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Misty Albion gets misty a lot, but it rarely gets properly foggy. Fog transforms the world into another dimention: one where sounds are soft, views are mysterious, and where mood swings from one end of the spectrum to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tip my hat to anyone who…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Misty Albion gets misty a lot, but it rarely gets properly foggy. Fog transforms the world into another dimention: one where sounds are soft, views are mysterious, and where mood swings from one end of the spectrum to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tip my hat to anyone who had the resiliency to keep exercising outdoors during this winter.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/snowfall-in-cambrdige/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Snowfall in Cambridge</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-05-11T11:49:13+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-04-28T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/snowfall-in-cambrdige/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is from last December, and I should have posted it for months now. In Cambridge, snow, that actually stays visible is rare; rare enough that with Nora, we usually get up for that one night when this tends to happen - The Night of The Winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, th…&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/snowfall-in-cambrdige/snowfall-in-cambrdige_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="92961"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is from last December, and I should have posted it for months now. In Cambridge, snow, that actually stays visible is rare; rare enough that with Nora, we usually get up for that one night when this tends to happen - The Night of The Winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, th…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is from last December, and I should have posted it for months now. In Cambridge, snow, that actually stays visible is rare; rare enough that with Nora, we usually get up for that one night when this tends to happen - The Night of The Winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this year, it lasted even shorter, but we still got a glimpse of a morning snowfall. Probably the only good thing of the lockdowns were that the city never got too busy with traffic, and a short walk in the morning before work became possible.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/mountains-of-la-palma/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Mountains of La Palma</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-05-11T11:49:13+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-04-27T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/mountains-of-la-palma/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;La Palma is a tiny island with huge mountains, and with spectacular possibilities for outstanding sights.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/mountains-of-la-palma/mountains-of-la-palma_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="46068"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;La Palma is a tiny island with huge mountains, and with spectacular possibilities for outstanding sights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La Palma is a tiny island with huge mountains, and with spectacular possibilities for outstanding sights.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/waterfall-of-clouds/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Waterfall of clouds</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-05-11T11:49:14+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-04-26T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/waterfall-of-clouds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been meaning to post this picture for a while now, but I kept forgetting it. The scene is from La Palma, the Canary Island; if you get up early enough and get to the right spot, there's a high chance you'll be greeted by a constantly moving waterfall…&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/waterfall-of-clouds/waterfall-of-clouds_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="123428"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been meaning to post this picture for a while now, but I kept forgetting it. The scene is from La Palma, the Canary Island; if you get up early enough and get to the right spot, there's a high chance you'll be greeted by a constantly moving waterfall…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been meaning to post this picture for a while now, but I kept forgetting it. The scene is from La Palma, the Canary Island; if you get up early enough and get to the right spot, there's a high chance you'll be greeted by a constantly moving waterfall of clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However: if you're at the same spot as us, than in the empty parking lot, you might find yourself feeding ravens instead who are friendly enough to land on your arm. Oh, and those pines smell absolutely wonderful when the weather is hot enough.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
  <atom:entry>
    <atom:id>https://petermolnar.net/photo/dadou-road/</atom:id>
    <atom:title>Dadou Road</atom:title>
    <atom:updated>2021-05-11T11:49:12+00:00</atom:updated>
    <atom:published>2021-04-25T09:00:00+01:00</atom:published>
    <atom:author>
      <atom:name>Peter Molnar</atom:name>
    </atom:author>
    <atom:link href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/dadou-road/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <atom:category>photo</atom:category>
    <atom:summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's strange which pictures and scenes stay with you. Close to the end of our journes in China in 2019 we were back in Hangzhou, only to learn that it was basically impossible to get into restaurants late in the evening - read: after 20:00. We ended up go…&lt;/p&gt;</atom:summary>
    <atom:link rel="enclosure" href="https://petermolnar.net/photo/dadou-road/dadou-road_large.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="89075"/>
    <atom:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's strange which pictures and scenes stay with you. Close to the end of our journes in China in 2019 we were back in Hangzhou, only to learn that it was basically impossible to get into restaurants late in the evening - read: after 20:00. We ended up go…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's strange which pictures and scenes stay with you. Close to the end of our journes in China in 2019 we were back in Hangzhou, only to learn that it was basically impossible to get into restaurants late in the evening - read: after 20:00. We ended up going to the food market of the closest mall, because that was open till 22:00. On our way back, after a rather rainy day, the streets were mostly empty, including this normally busy with people and tourists street.&lt;/p&gt;</atom:content>
  </atom:entry>
</atom:feed>
